Tyom Semonov

Frontend Developer

Passionate developer with over 13 years of professional experience in building high-traffic complex websites and applications using web standards and best practices for desktops and mobile devices.

Great attention to detail, code maintainability and performance. Keen learner in multiple disciplines. Advocate of datadriven, user-centred, accessible, mobile-first design.

CORE SKILLS

- JavaScript
- Node.js
- Webpack
- Express
- React
- CSS/PostCSS/Sass
- HTML5
- Git/GitHub
- Accessibility
- Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch

CURRENT FOCUS

- Node.js
- Express
- React/Redux
- Vue.js
- github.com/tyom
- in linkedin.com/in/tyoms

tyom.semonov.com tyom@semonov.com

EXPERIENCE

Details for the last 3 years. For more see tyom.semonov.com

October 2017 - November 2017

BCG Digital Ventures

Senior Frontend Engineer CONTRACTOR

Working in a team responsible for building interactive dashboard with collaboration tools for a large cement producer. The project was eventually taken over by the client to be built in-house.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (React, Redux, Jest, Webpack), CSS Modules, Git

May 2017 - October 2017

Department for International Trade (DIT)

Senior Frontend Developer CONTRACTOR

Working in a medium-sized team developing a complex CRM application in Node.js with Python backend.

The application was built to support a wide range of browsers (including legacy). The constraints led to interesting innovations to fulfil the user and business needs. Vastly improved development tools and processes.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (Node.js, Express, Webpack, Mocha, Nightwatch.js, Nunjucks), Sass, Git

November 2016 - April 2017

NHS Digital

Senior Frontend Developer CONTRACTOR

Working in a team on transformation of the NHS.UK. Created and maintained common components library which documents and shows usage of various components that make various NHS.UK online services, such as beta.nhs.uk.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (Node.js, Express, Webpack, Gulp, Mocha), Sass, Git, Fractal

July 2016 - November 2016

Barclays

Senior Frontend Developer CONTRACTOR

As the only front-end developer I was working on internal tool for managing risks in agile development of projects within the bank.

Responsible for ensuring that the application is meeting Barclays standards for accessibility and usability. Introduced a number of frontend best practices the team. Optimised and improved maintainability of the front-end codebase.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (AngularJS, Webpack), Unit testing (Jasmine, Karma, Spock), CSS/Less, Git, Jenkins

December 2015 - June 2016

BBC

Senior JavaScript Application Developer CONTRACTOR

Working in a small team responsible for launching the BBC Three online service.

Building universal BBC Three components in React and BBC Morph modules in node.js. Using BBC GEL design framework with focus on reusability, unit/acceptance testing, performance and consistent cross-device/browser experience.

Designed and built a number of BBC Three specific features as well as general improvements to performance and organisation of the codebase.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (React, Node.js, Express, Gulp, Webpack), Unit testing (Mocha, skin-deep, WebDriver, BrowserStack, Galen Framework), CSS/PostCSS, Git/GitHub, Jenkins

September 2014 - December 2015

UK Ministry of Justice

Developer CONTRACTOR

Responsible for front-end development and design of public service to check if one can get legal aid. Continuous development of functional prototypes used in rounds of user-testing to regularly test hypothesis and validate design decisions. Later maintained the call-centre counterpart application written in AngularJS.

Developed component libraries and generated service style guides. Built NPM packages to ease the exchange and development of assets and components across government websites and web applications.

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (Node.js, AngularJS, Nightwatch.js, PhantomJS, Gulp, Webpack), CSS/Sass, Ruby (Rails, Middleman), Python (Django, Flask, Jinja), Git/GitHub, Jenkins, Graphviz, Google Analytics, Sketch

May 2012 - September 2014

state.com (defunct)

Frontend Developer

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (Dojo Toolkit, AMD, Node.js, AngularJS, Buster.js, D3.js, Grunt), CSS/Sass, SVG, Ruby (Rails, Middleman), Git/GitHub, MongoDB, Redis, Photoshop/Illustrator

January 2012 - May 2012

VisualDNA

Frontend Developer

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript/CoffeeScript (jQuery, Backbone.js), CSS, PHP (Twig), SVN/Git, Photoshop

February 2010 - December 2011

streetlife.com

Designer/Developer

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (jQuery), CSS, Python (Django, Flask, Jinja), Vagrant, Puppet, Git/GitHub, Photoshop/Illustrator, OmniGraffle

January 2010 - February 2010

DigitasLBi

Interface Developer CONTRACTOR

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript (jQuery), CSS, HTML, Photoshop

December 2007 - November 2009

Microsoft

UX Designer

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript, HTML/XML, CSS, Script#, C#, Photoshop/Illustrator

September 2006 - December 2007

Multimap (defunct)

Web Developer

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Perl, Template Toolkit, Perforce, Photoshop/Illustrator

October 2005 - August 2006

Sportingbet

Web Developer

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MediaWiki, Photoshop

February 2004 - October 2005

Freelancing

Design, Development

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Photoshop/Illustrator

EDUCATION

1997 - 2000 (Ukraine)

Sumy State University

Linguistics and Translation